

Profile: I'm Geoffrey Lehée, Open Source, Linux, Python, and DevOps advocate. I love working with a team to build and maintain well-designed infrastructure, APIs, and software. All this stuff hosted on well-configured and highly secured infrastructure in the cloud. From deploying infrastructure and software with Bash scripts, then the Ansible revolution happened and now Terraform at the age of infrastructure-as-code has been an amazing journey and that's exactly what I love to do. The rest of my time is for system hacking & security. It's been many years since I am a digital nomad, from France to Japan and now based in Europe.

Experiences:

- Senior Open Source Developer & DevOps, OpenCraft; (full remote); 2019-now OpenCraft is a full-remote company dedicated to the Open Source OpenEdx educational software backed by Harvard and MIT.
 - o Open Source contributions: Open edX and related software
 - Developed the Harvard <u>LabXchange</u> platform (Django, Typescript, ReactJS)
 - o Python, Django, Typescript, ReactJS
 - o AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker, Google Cloud Platform
- Python/Go SRE, Ulule; Paris, France (full remote); 2017-2019

 <u>Ulule</u> is the EU leader of crowdfunding with more than 2m users and 110m € collected.
 - Django, Flask & Celery
 - Gin & Chi
 - Proxmox, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Docker, Postgres
 - Redis, Ansible, Grafana, ElasticSearch, HAProxy
- Python developer, Oasiswork; Nantes, France (partial remote); 2015-2017
 Oasiswork is an email and groupware integrator which develops its e-mailing campaign solution.
 - Django with RESTful API (django-rest-framework)
 - Celery with RabbitMQ for load balancing
 - E-mail routing for IP rate limiting/warm-up
 - Redis, RabbitMQ, Grafana, ElasticSearch
 - <u>Crunchmail</u>: Open Source mailing software
- Python developer, Jurismarchés; Nantes, France; 2013-2015
 Jurismarchés (now OctopusMind) develops his own public tenders tool backed by Django, AngularJs, Postgresql, and ElasticSearch.
 - Django with RESTful API (<u>django-rest-framework</u>)
 - Dynamical MVC front-end with two ways data binding
 - Celery with RabbitMQ for load balancing
 - Full-text searching through ElasticSearch

- Linux Sysadmin, Capensis; Carquefou, France (partial remote); 2011-2013 Capensis is an open-source solutions integrator.
 - European Parliament (Belgium) monitoring solution with Shinken
 - Adeo datacenter monitoring (Lille, France)
 - La Poste datacenter monitoring (Nantes, France)
 - Linux & security class training
- Python developer, Reaklab; Mons, Belgium (remote-internship); 01/2011-02/2011
- Linux Sysadmin, Makina Corpus, Nantes, France (internship); 05/2010-08/2010

Skills:

- Development: Python, Golang, Rust, Perl, Bash, HTML, CSS, Javascript, and LUA
- Web: ReactJS, Typescript, WebPack, AngularJS, Gin, Chi, Flask, Django & Gunicorn
- System: Linux, Ubuntu, Debian, and RedHat
- Databases: MongoDB, Postgresql, Mysql, ElasticSearch, and RedHat
- Network: Nginx, Apache, HAProxy, Nagios, Shinken, and Prometheus
- Automation and orchestration: Terraform, Ansible, Kubernetes, and Consul
- Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Kibana, and CloudWatch
- Security: Vault, Boundary, Consul and GPG
- Tools: AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Sentry, Jenkins, Gitlab, and Github
- Team methods: Agile Scrum, asynchronous tools, and remote processes
- Languages: French and English (read and write), and Japanese beginner

Education:

- BTS Informatique de Gestion; La Joliverie Nantes, France; 2011
- BAC STI Génie Électronique; Montaigu, France; 2009

Misc.:

- Contributor on open source projects
- Many open-source software developments on Gitlab/Github
- Nomadic life and traveler. Lived in Japan for two years, Germany and Sweden.
- SciFi and Fantasy reader (Philip K. Dick, H.P. Lovecraft, A. Douglas..)
- Studying Japanese
- Book readers and anime lover
- FOSDEM 2011 Brussels BELGIUM
- Nuit Du Hack 2012 (Hacking Festival) Paris, France